# Suraya Clemens

### **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

www.suraya.xyz surayaclemens@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/suraya-clemens github.com/surayaclemens

### **PROFILE**

I see web development as a tool to combine my love of creating cool things with my responsibility to work towards a more equitable future, and seek engagements that prioritize accessibility & inclusivity along with innovation.

Outside my work in the tech sector, my background in linguistics provided me with practical experience in both logical and humanist thinking, and my academic accomplishments demonstrate that I execute top quality work.

Complementing these hard skills is my extensive experience in customer service, which cultivated my ability to

My colleagues know me as an excellent communicator, thorough problem solver, initiative-taker, and big fan of jokes.

identify and meet interpersonal needs,

and form positive relationships.

### **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular, React, Express, Node, Firebase, SQL, DOM APIs, Web APIs, User Auth, OAuth, Heroku, GCP, Docker, GitHub, Figma, Jira, Agile Methodology

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Comprehensive list on LinkedIn

## Software Engineer - Full-stack Web Developer | Cedulify

AUG 2022 - Present, REMOTE/MONTREAL, QC

- Front-end: responsible for all UI, implementation of accessibility requirements, responsive design adaptation
- Back-end: endpoints for API calls and CRUD operations, database structuring to optimize internationalization & localization, server events to work with Meta Conversions API
- Product: close collaboration with design team and CEO on user flows, interface, feature priorities
- Project management: restructured company's Jira for stronger efficiency and communication, applied Agile methodology, implemented various systems to manage dev team's work
- Within 6 months: shipped product from ideation to production using entirely new stack, implemented internationalization & localization for a bilingual app, created UX flows that were approved and implemented

# Research Assistant | Syrians Learning English for Employment in Canada (SLEEC), University of Victoria

SEP 2021 - APR 2022, VICTORIA, BC

- Planned and conducted academic study within SLEEC pilot program to inform the language-learning experience of refugees and newcomers to Canada
- Executed through survey composition, literature review, participant interviews, qualitative content analysis, synthesis of findings + graphic design for presentation, public speaking

### Web Designer | Van Brothers Forming Ltd.

DEC 2020 - MAR 2021, REMOTE/VANCOUVER, BC

- Designed and produced a re-branded marketing site to meet industry standards and attract bigger clients
- Exceeded stakeholder goals by refining site architecture, improving UX and modernizing UI

### **EDUCATION**

# **BrainStation | Diploma, Web Development**

JUL 2022, VANCOUVER, CA

### University of Victoria | Bachelor of Arts, Linguistics

APR 2022, VICTORIA, CA

• GPA 4.0, Undergraduate Research Award, President's Scholarship

### **PROJECTS**

- Ayajuthem Tetris: Gamified learning for Indigenous language revitalization
- Alatúlie: English to Elvish translator